Guide to the Stanley S. Slotkin and Mark A. Slotkin Collection of Title Page Facsimiles with Attached Original Leaves from Books Published 1534-approximately 1750
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Stanley S. Slotkin and Mark A. Slotkin Collection of Title Page Facsimiles with Attached Original Leaves from Books Published 1534-approximately 1750.
approximately 1534-1750.
Slotkin, Stanley S.;; Slotkin, Mark A.
0.5 cubic feet (1 box)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Title page facsimiles and original leaves collected by Stanley S. Slotkin and Mark A. Slotkin.
Biographical Note
Stanley S. Slotkin (1905-1997) was an American businessman and philanthropist based in Los Angeles, California. Aside from his professional and charitable involvement in the medical field, he was also interested in early manuscripts and printed books, as well as archaeology, particularly of religious sites. His son, Mark A. Slotkin (1943-), an antiques dealer, succeeded him in these interests.
Scope and Content Note
Stanley S. Slotkin and Mark A. Slotkin Collection of Title Page Facsimiles with Attached Original Leaves from Books Published 1534-approximately 1750 includes leaves from a variety of early printed books, including Bibles and devotional texts; works on history, law, and philosophy; and classical texts.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the
Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Subjects:
Early printed books; History--Early works to 1800; Law--England--Early works to 1800; Philosophy--Early works to 1800; Theology--Early works to 1800
Document Types:
Antiphonaries; Bibles
VCL Categories
Printing and Publishing
Encoding Information
Finding aid encoded by Mark Seidl, February 2021.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Stanley S. Slotkin and Mark A. Slotkin.
Container List
- Hebraica, Chaldea, Graecaque, and Latina Nomina... Antwerpae (Antwerp), Martinum Caesarem, 1534; (4 leaves: 378, 379, 380, 408) (1.1)
- Pliny the Elder. C. Plini secundi historiae mundi libri XXXVII. Lugdunae (Lyons), Ioannem Frellionium, 1563; (4 leaves: 425, 501, 505, 507) (1.2)
- Massorah Rabbinical Bible, 1610; (4 leaves) (1.3)
- Joost Lips (Justus Lipsus). Iusti Lipsi V.C. Opera Omnia Antverpiae (Antwerp), ex Officina Plantiniana Balthasaris Moreti, 1637; (4 leaves: 505, 507, 509, 515) (1.4)
- Johannes Buxtorf. Johannis Buxtorfi P. Tiberias, sive Commentarius Masorethicus Triplex Basileae (Basel), Johannis Buxtorfi, Jacobi Deckeri, 1665; (4 leaves) (1.5)
- Antiphonale cisterciense juxta novum ordinis brevarium dispositum. Parisius (Paris), Fredericus Leoua, 1690; (4 leaves: 437, 467, 469, 499) (1.6)
- Ludovico Maria Sinistrari. Ludovicum Sinistrari Practica Criminalis Illustrata. Romae (Rome), Joannis Jacobi Komarek, S. Angelum Custodem, 1693; (4 leaves: 397, 553, 555, 557) (1.7)
- F Natali Alexandro. Theologia domatica et moralis secundum ordinem catechismi concilii tridentini. Parisiis (Paris), Antoni Dezallier, 1703; (4 leaves: 59, 61, 63, 319) (1.8)
- Edward, Earl of Claredon. The History of the Rebellion and Civil Wars in England. Oxford, the Theatre, 1707; (4 leaves: 171, 475, 477, 479) (1.9)
- A Table of all the Publick and Private Statues, 1734; (4 leaves: 21, 375, 377, 379) (1.10)
- Crescentius Krisper. Philosophia scholae scotisticae. Matthiae Wolff, 1735; (4 leaves: 3, 5, 174, 317) (1.11)
- Prophetae priores, approximately 1750; (4 leaves: leaves: 479, 525, 527, 529) (1.12)